It's Autumn or Fall for my American viewers,
campfires, marshmallows we're going to take
Frank and make S'mores ice cream so if you want
to see how, let's get a move on and make it.
What is a S'more for those that don't know I don't
why you wouldn't know if you live under a rock
but you know a smore is s'mores are are uh graham
cracker biscuit if you will cookie for those that
are going to moan about me calling it a biscuit
with a toasted marshmallow with a layer of or a
slab of chocolate on top and then another graham
cracker cookie on top so we've got three things
we've got graham cracker marshmallow chocolate
that is the atypical s'more s'mores what we're
going to do is we're going to break that down
and do it in ice cream form so we're going to
use the marshmallows in the ice cream base we're
then going to make a gram cracker crumb that we
can put through it and our chocolate we're going
to do a straciatella you can do chocolate sauce
you can do chocolate ice cream with marshmallow
pieces and gram cracker crumb you can do loads
of different variations you do gr and cracker
ice cream with a mar marshmallow swirl with
like a chocolate sauce loads of different ways
of doing this but today that's what we're going
to do marshmallow ice cream gram cracker add in
chocolate straciatella so let's get on and make it
so it's quite a complex make but it's definitely
this thing's getting too tight around this area
um quite a complex M there's a few things we need
to do um this is the most important one we need to
toast our marshmallows bacon sheet we need 327g
of these there or thereabouts 330g close enough
get rid of these we need to account for sugars
in marshmallows they're very high in sugar so
these are approximately 28g marshmallows and
of that is 17g of sugar a marshmallow is 28g
and it's got 17g of sugar per marshmallow so
easy way to do that is we do 17 divided by 28
gives us 0.60 it means it's 60% sugar content in
that marshmallow Okay that that's what you get
there are other ways of doing that you can do
28g divide it into 1% which would be 0.28 then
you divide 17 by 0.28 gives you the same number
you know but that's important because if you buy
marshmallows are ultra low in sugar then the
recipe won't work cuz is not enough sugar in
it to work correctly so 60% sugar marshmallows per
marshmallow 28g, 17g of sugar please account for
that don't put a comment in say oh my my ice cream
went solid as a rock I didn't change anything and
then I said well what did you change oh I used
those marshmallows it got zero sugar the're well
it's your own fault there we go marshmallows
we need to toast those get the oven on we want
it quite hot so we're putting up to 420f and and
we're going to put those in when it's ready that's
going to give us time to get the rest of the ice
cream base prepared it's quite a big batch I'm
doing here 2L batch so simply cut it in half if
you want to do one liter 2L is enough to do four
Ninja creamy tubs two ninja creamy tubs and a
a one L churn one L churn um two ninja creamy
Deluxe plus a bit on extra on the side you know
whatever do whatever size batch works for you
but this is a 2 L batch cuz I want to eat a
[__] ton of smalles ice cream so 562g of
milk 857g of 33% whipping cream big batch probably
should have gone to the next pan size up but you
know that's how I roll in this I always use a pan
that's just too bloody small into that we're going
to put 110g of sugar not a lot of sugar because
the marshmallows have got the majority of it in
110g into that we are adding 38g of dextrose
if you don't have dextrose you don't want to
use dextrose you can use like glucose syrup
corn syrup 105g of skin milk powder important
skin milk powder increases milk solids without
increasing fat cont content that's it that's
our ice cream base our marshmallows are going to
be going into this base there's no stabilizer in
this not putting a stabilizer in this why because
marshmallows have got gelatin in to create that
form gelatin is a reasonable ice cream stabilizer
we're going to use all of the gelatin that's in
those marshmallows 327g worth, to stabilize our
ice cream base no need to add another one so we're
going to get this on hob we're going to get this
warmed up we don't need to Super cook this we just
need to get everything homogenized and we'll
come back once the marshmallows have been in
the oven and are ready to come out putting these
in now to toast the marshmallows we need fire so
I'm going to use my Baker's torch use whatever
you can use a grill or what do they call them
in North America a broiler you can use fire you
can use rub two sticks together we're going to
burn them we're going to burn these marshmallows
we're what we're doing is the oven is softening
the marshmallows up they're going to expand as the
air expands inside the marshmallows due to being
heated they're going to Super soften we're going
to take them out of the oven and deal with them
like that so I'll come back in a second we got our
blender out ready cuz this is how we're going to
emulsify all of this mix but whilst this is on the
oven's going we're going to cook our gr cracker
crumb so for that we need we need some butter we
60g of butter there we go and we're just going
to melt this in the microwave here we go not going
crazy boil it burn it wherever just melt it gently
we don't need that we're not bringing our up to
85 °C/ 185°F because there's no stabilizer in
there we are just homogenizing that mix so we're
we bring it up to you know 50-60° C to make sure
that our sugar is dissolved our milk powder is
dissolved and Incorporated so easy way to to see
that without thermometer is when the steam starts
to come off the top you know you're about there
so into our melted butter we're going to add add
in 150g of our Graham crumb take graham crackers,
smash them up buy them buy it like this
whatever works for you and just gently stir it
together it's going to be a really nice buttery
mix don't make it dry if you make it too dry it
just disintegrates we need to cook this anyway
and we're cooking this because we're putting
one more ingredient into here you can put in
Honey corn syrup glucose plain old invert sugar
whatever works for you I'm using golden syrup we
just going to put approximately 2 tablespoons so
you know that's that's about 30g to 40g one two
you don't have to go mad you can put Less in if
you want to but we're putting that in not only
will it bring this mix together it creates this
super kind of chew that you can't achieve any
other way what we're going to do is going to
take our pan here and get that in here there
we go we've patted that down I'm going to Li
this you know me a marsh smow have got another
5 minutes in the oven keep an eye on them every
oven's different I've put mine on the middle
shelf you put them at the top and you've got
a top heating element you're going to burn
the marshmallows really really quickly what
we're looking for is for the marshmallows
to expand become super soft and toasted
so let's have a
look they're ready to come out is Real
Time marshmallows let me get
my phone so you can see a
nice there we go look marshmallows
they' ex expanded they've toasted
we haven't finished there yet youve got smoke
alarm be prepared we're going
to burn these we I mean really
get that toast don't be afraid of
setting them on fire that's what we
want right that's if that doesn't set
the smoke alarm off I don't know what
we turn that back on we're going to put
our gr cracker base in the oven doesn't
need to be in there long you know kind of
10 12 minutes we you're going to see that
butter and the invert sugar just start to
Bubble Up don't let it go too mad all right
so we've got our burnt marshmallows we
want that burn this we want that that's
just burnt sugar that is what adds this
s'mores flavor that is what makes this as
good as it really is but now we have
a problem that problem is we have to
get all of this into here it may take two
goes we've got our base which is about 50°
something like that we going to take a ladle
and and get some in here we don't want to put
the marshmallows in the bottom but I'm also
going to make an absolute triumphant Mess by
trying to pour that in there so now we need to get
some of this in there this is where the the fun
comes you're going to need take a couple
of implements and we are simply going to
get that in there if you are looking
for a non messy ice cream this is not
it now we can pour a little bit
more base in doing this in two
goes, blend it for 30 seconds
seconds oh that
smells good color we we also burn
those marshmallows to get that color in
there now we can put the rest of our base in
anyway that is our marshmallow base done super
hard work it's not really hard work it's
just sticky work yeah the utensils have
sort utensils have sorted themselves out in that
warm base the marshmallows come off we are good
to go as we're cooling this base down if you're
making this in a traditional churn machine you've
got a bit of time to play you've got the cooling
time of this you can make your gram cracker crumb
then no problems whatsoever if you're using the
creamy your chances are you won't be making a 2L
base like this anyway you'll be making you know
a half liter or a 1L base in which case it will
all fit in a blender all in one go so you don't
have to worry about doing multiple batches like me
anyway let's get this in the fridge cooling down
lot of bloody talk in this one see you later so
after the base is completely chilled down going to
take it out of the fridge and give it a nice good
stir just to make sure everything's mixed up and
then pop it in your pre-chill machine to churn now
while we're doing that we're going to take some
chocolate this is milk chocolate valona didn't
have enough so I topped off with cacao Barry milk
chocolate added in in some coconut oil and melted
it in a microwave until it was melted then I took
our chopped gr cracker crumb put it into small CM
cubes delicious and then at the final stage of the
charm we're going to drop in our melted chocolate
to form the Strat aella and load up our ice cream
tubs with our ice cream our graham cracker crumb
and then a layer of our chocolate on top of that
and then again we're going to go in with some more
ice cream some more Graham crumb and finally top
it off with some more chocolate and a couple more
pieces of that delicious crumb and pop it in the
freezer smalles ice cream for 2024 I do this I try
and do this flavor every year and that is where we
are man that looks good let me get some dished up
s'mores is one of my favorite flavors of ice cream
it's just a delicious combination
let's see how this one turned
out delicious marshmallowy ice cream base it's
like pillowy slight vanilla tinge to it that
underlying taste of that toasted marshmallow outer
coming through all of that's given the color to
this base which is a beautiful tinge of taupe Flex
of black throughout oh it's delicious the graham
cracker pieces with that addition of the invert
sugar corn syrup honey whatever you want to use
gives it super chewy but not too chewy kind of
texture breaks through that ice cream then the
glorious chocolate fleks throughout layered with
that chocolate layer through the middle this is
a winner I'm making some good ice creams this year
so this one is super delicious you got to try this
one thanks very much all my patreon supporters
they're growing in numbers you're amazing people
and I love you for supporting this channel without
you I couldn't do this I'm going to put a nice big
list here of all of you so huge thank you to those
big thank you to my YouTube members too you're
also grown in numbers we're going to be at 12,000
subscribers soon which is incredible who knew that
12,000 people wanted to watch me make ice cream
anyway let's jibber jabber there's been enough of
that in this video I will see you next week when
we do something super unique in the Ninja creamy